smtp2go.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy - SMTP2GO

## Log In

Don't have an account? Register here

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Sand Dune Mail Ltd (“we”, “us”, “our”) collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a “User”) of the [http://www.smtp2go.com](http://www.smtp2go.com/) website (“Site”). This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by us. The use of information processed through our services shall be limited to the purpose of providing the services for which our customers have engaged us.

If a User has an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

## Personal information

We may collect personal information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our Site, register on the Site, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for personal data, as appropriate, which will include Users’ name, email address, phone number and organization information. We will collect personal information from Users only if they consent voluntarily to submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personal information or withdraw their consent for us to process that information at any time, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities.  
All personal data provided to us is processed and stored securely, for no longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. We will comply with our obligations and safeguard Users rights under the EU Regulation 2016/679 – the General Data Protection Regulation (known as “the GDPR”) at all times.  
Our use of personal data will always have a lawful basis, either because it is necessary for our performance of a contract with a User, because that User has consented to our use of their personal data (e.g. by subscribing to emails), or because it is in our legitimate interests to do so.  
Users may access certain areas of our Site without providing any personal data at all. However, to use all features and functions available on our Site, Users may be required to submit or allow for the collection of certain data.  
Users have the right to withdraw their consent to us using their personal data at any time, and to request that we delete it.  
Under the GDPR, which this privacy policy and our use of personal data have been designed to uphold, Users have the right to:

  1. be informed about our collection and use of personal data;
  2. have access to the personal data we hold about them;
  3. rectification if any personal data we hold about them is inaccurate or incomplete;
  4. be forgotten (meaning the right to ask us to delete any personal data we hold about them). We only hold personal data for a limited time, as explained in this privacy policy but if a User would like us to delete it sooner, they should contact us using the details in this privacy policy;
  5. restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data;
  6. data portability (obtaining a copy of their personal data to re-use with another service or organisation);
  7. object to us using their personal data for particular purposes; and
  8. rights with respect to automated decision making and profiling.

## Passive Collection

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our Site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the Site.  
If combined with other information we know about Users from previous visits to our Site, the data possibly could be used to identify them personally, even if such Users are not signed in to our Site.

## Tracking Technologies

We and our partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the Site, track Users’ movements around the Site, and to gather demographic information about our User base as a whole. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if they choose to disable cookies, it may limit their use of certain features or functions on our Site or service.  
We use cookies in the following ways:

  1. to track how our Site is used by Users;
  2. to record whether Users have seen specific messages we display on our Site;
  3. to keep Users signed into our Site;
  4. to record User’s answers to surveys and questionnaires on our Site while they complete them; and
  5. to record the conversation thread during a live chat with our support team

## Behavioral Targeting or Advertising

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about a User’s activities on this Site and other sites in order to provide Users with advertising based upon their browsing activities and interests. If a User wishes to not have this information used for the purpose of serving them interest-based ads, [you may opt-out by clicking here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt Users out of being served ads. Users will continue to receive generic ads.

## How we use collected information

We may collect and use Users’ personal information for the following purposes:

  *  **To improve customer service**  
Information Users provide helps us respond to their customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.
  *  **To personalize user experience**  
We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site.
  *  **To improve our Site**  
We may use feedback Users provide to improve our products and services.
  *  **To process payments**  
We may use the information Users provide about themselves when placing an order only to provide service to that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service.
  *  **To run a promotion, contest, survey or other Site feature**  
To send Users information they agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to them.
  *  **To send periodic emails**  
We may use the email address to send User information and updates pertaining to their order. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email or User may contact us via our Site at the [SMTP2GO Contact Page](http://www.smtp2go.com/contact).

We will not, however, send Users any unsolicited marketing or spam and will take all reasonable steps to ensure that we fully protect Users’ rights and comply with our obligations under the GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.

## How we protect User information

The security of both our customers’ data and any 3rd party data we process on their behalf is very important to us. All personal data will be processed and stored by us safely and securely for no longer than is necessary in light of the reason for which it was first collected by us. We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of Users personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. If a User has any questions about the security of their personal information, they can contact us at [ticket@smtp2go.com](mailto:ticket@smtp2go.com)

Sensitive and private data exchange between the Site and its Users happens over a SSL secured communication channel and is encrypted and protected with digital signatures. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If a User has any questions about security on our Site, they can contact us at the [SMTP2GO Contact Page](http://www.smtp2go.com/contact).

## Sharing User personal information

We will share Users’ personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell, trade, or rent Users personal information to others. We may provide Users’ personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as offering customer service and payment processing. These companies are authorized by us to use Users’ personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us and we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that User personal data will be handled safely, securely, and in accordance with their rights, our obligations, and the obligations of the third party under relevant data protection law. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this privacy policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Users. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal information regarding visitors and Users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above.

We may sometimes use third party data processors that are located outside of the European Economic Area (“the EEA”) (the EEA consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein). Where we transfer any personal data outside the EEA, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that Users’ data is treated as safely and securely as it would be within the EEA and under the GDPR.

In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may also disclose personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect Users’ safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, to any other third party with the relevant User’s prior consent to do so.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, Users will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership or uses of their personal information, as well as any choices they may have regarding their personal information.

## Accessing User data

Upon request we will provide Users with information about whether we hold any of their personal information. If a User’s personal information changes they may correct, update or amend it by making the change on their account settings page. If a User no longer desires our service, or wishes to request any changes to their personal data directly, they may do so at the [SMTP2GO Contact Page](http://www.smtp2go.com/contact) or by contacting us by email or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to User request to access within 30 days.

We acknowledge that Users have the right to ask for a copy of any of their personal data held by us (where such data is held). Under the GDPR, no fee is payable, and we will provide any and all information in response to a User’s request for their data free of charge. Please contact us for more details using the contact information below.

We have no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data we process on behalf of our Users. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query to the relevant User (the data controller)

We will retain User information, and the information we process on behalf of Users as our customer, for as long as a User account is active or as needed to provide our services. We will retain and use this information only as long as is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Information related to 3rd party data collected through our services

We collect information under the direction of our customers and have no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal information our customers process. An individual who seeks access, who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data or withdraw consent to further contact from a User should direct their query to the our customer whom they interact with directly (the data controller). If that customer requests that we remove the data in question, we will respond to their request within 30 days.

## Storage of email data

Our operators and compliance personnel may need to review email communications sent by any User, whether or not they are addressed to us, if we become aware of possible breaches of the [terms of service](http://www.smtp2go.com/terms), including sending spam. This is only to be conducted in exceptional circumstances, if there is a strong suspicion that a User may have breached the terms of service. One email per one hundred sent is securely stored for such a purpose, for a period of 35 days, before deletion. We can disable such storage for trusted accounts, upon request. Email headers for all emails are kept for 35 days before deletion and can be viewed in the User’s control panel.

## Storage of personal data

Personal data for Users located within the EEA will only be stored by us within the EEA.  
We have taken all suitable measures to safeguard and secure personal data collected through our Site.

## Third party websites

Users may find content on our Site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website’s own terms and policies. We encourage Users to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site they visit.

Our Site also includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook button, Twitter, and Widgets, such as the Share this button. These Features may collect Users’ IP address, which page Users are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. User interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Blog

Our Site offers a publicly accessible blog. Users should be aware that any information they provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of User personal information from our blog or community forum, Users should contact us at the [SMTP2GO Contact Page](http://www.smtp2go.com/contact). In some cases, we may not be able to remove personal information, in which case we will let the User know if we are unable to do so and why.

## Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our Site in addition to other endorsements. With User consent we may post their testimonial along with their name. If a User wishes us to update or delete their testimonial, they can contact us at the [SMTP2GO Contact Page](http://www.smtp2go.com/contact).

## Surveys

We may provide Users with the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our Site. If Users choose to participate, we will request certain personal information from them. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and Users therefore have a choice whether or not to consent to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). We will only keep this information for as long as necessary as made clear at the time that it is provided, and we shall delete the information after the relevant time.

## Changes to this privacy policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify Users client by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in their account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage Users to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## User acceptance of these terms

By using this Site, Users signify their acceptance of this privacy policy and [terms of service](http://www.smtp2go.com/terms). If a User does not agree to this privacy policy, then we ask that they please do not use our Site. Continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this privacy policy will be deemed to indicate a User’s acceptance of those changes.

## Contacting us

If a User has any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of this Site, or a User’s dealings with this Site, please contact us at:

SMTP2GO (Sand Dune Mail Ltd)  
96-106 Manchester Street, Christchurch 8011, New Zealand  
Email: ticket@smtp2go.com 

This document was last updated on May 4, 2018

## Ready to get started?

Try SMTP2GO free for as long as you like:

Try SMTP2GO Free → [Paid plans](https://www.smtp2go.com/pricing) available for over 1,000 emails/month.
